Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number nine.
We are asked to find the time complexity of this for loop and this four algorithm.
This for Loop is printing a statement, just printing the eye and that is of complexity.
All of one first.
Now.
As I told you in the previous videos, we are going to pay attention to that initial values do the stopping
values and the incremental value OK the way they increment.
So this loop will go through from one will start from one fill and affect the effect I is less than
or equal factorial of.
And this is a method called factorial and we pass and we calculate the factorial of N..
So in mathematics, the factorial of any number is that the number of times the following number at
minus one times the number minus total reaching one.
So for example, if I have if I have like five factorial is equal to five times.
Four times, three times, two times one.
So the stopping condition of this is one five times four is 20 times or three.
60 times two is equal to one 20.
For example, if we took an equal to five, we are going to go through this slope from one till one
to one.
OK, which is five factorial.
OK.
No.
I plus plus this will tell us that we are going to loop all through all the elements we are going to
iterate through all the elements of this loop.
OK.
And we are going to execute this statement around 120 times.
Therefore, if we entered like six factorial.
We are going to six times five times that, four times, three times, two times one.
So 120 times six is 600 and 720.
We are going to execute this.
720 times.
OK.
Therefore, this will this execution will depends on the factorial of the end.
OK, so we enter an equal to six, eight, one result at 720.
We enter five and equal to five.
It will result in 120 times execution of this statement.
Therefore, that completed this this exercise, the complexity of this algorithm is going to execute
the print I, according from a court or according to the range, from one to and factory.
OK.
And this is the trick in this question.
Making and understanding and factorial and the algorithms, so that complexity would be oh of and factorial.
And this is the worst.
And this is one of the worst algorithms and one of the worst oh, a big old notation, which is an error
factory.
For example, if we put an equal to eight, we are going to execute this statement.
This simple statement?
Forty two thousand three hundred twenty times.
This is an equal to eight.
What about an equal to 100 or one thousand one thousand or one million?
This will result in very big numbers, and this goes this algorithms to be a bad algorithm.